The problem with most skill based setups
is that they are great for solo
developers, but they're not so great
when you get into teams. With teams, or
when you're working on other people's
stuff, or building ideas for other
people, you will often need to triage
other people's ideas to figure out if
they're good or not, to even figure out
if they're worth building, to figure out
if it's a bug report, to see if you need
to reproduce it, all that stuff. And
this is very familiar to anyone who's
been building anything of reasonable
size for a while. And so, I have built a
skill for that. This skill is called
triage, and I run triage on every single
open source repo that I run. It's great
for working through GitHub issues, you
can plug it into Jira, you can plug it
into any backlog to essentially flesh
out that backlog and turn it into
actionable tasks that can be picked up
by an agent, or to reject it, or to do
all sorts of various things with it. The
thing that drives this is that it has a
essentially a state machine encoded into
labels. So, you have two category roles
currently, this may change in future. We
have a bug role and an enhancement role,
which is very, you know, that's well
known to anyone who's done any work with
triage. And then, you have five state
roles, and these are kind of up for
grabs as well, like this is um something
that I probably will expand on in the
future, but for now this is working for
me.
Each of these five state roles
corresponds to a state that the ticket
can be in. So, the ticket might be needs
triage, in other words, it needs a
maintainer to look at it. You know, it's
a paused the maintainer has actually
done that work. It might be that it
needs info, waiting on the reporter for
more information. It might be ready for
an agent to pick up, in other words,
it's fully specified, ready for an AFK
agent to go and slam through the task.
Or it might need a human to look at it
now and to actually implement it.
Or we do a won't fix, where it just will
not be actioned. This is a state machine
because every single triaged issue
should carry exactly one category role
and one state role. In other words, you
can't have it be ready for human and
needs triage at the same time. This is a
good old state machine, and that's
familiar to anyone who's followed my
career, you'll know I would love state
machines. So, the way you use triage is
you can use it in a bunch of different
ways. You can either use it to triage a
specific issue, you can triage the
entire backlog and say show me anything
that needs my attention now. You can
say, "Okay, let's move this one to ready
for agent." And by the way, ready for
agent is a nice one because in order to
move something to ready for agent, you
need to write a brief for the agent
that's going to pick it up. And we have
inside here a agent brief template,
which allows you to kind of write this
ticket really nicely. So, you're
probably thinking, "Okay, I get the
basics of this. Show me this in action."
Turns out we have a bunch of issues that
need triage in Sandcastle. So, that's
what I'm going to do. I'm going to show
you how to use this skill by triaging my
own repo. You can see there's a bunch of
stuff that's already in here. Some of
the stuff that's ready for agent that's
been put into a PR already, some that
kind of needs triage that I need to look
at again, some that's totally unlabeled,
some marked as won't fix. So, I'm going
to open up a new Claude session inside
my repo, and I'm going to say triage,
and then I'll say, "Just give me all of
the open issues." Or rather, just the
ones that I haven't triaged yet. So,
let's ping this off and see what
happens. It should go and explore the
repo. It should pick up that I'm using
GitHub issues, and yep, look at it go.
Okay, it can see there are nine
untriaged open issues. I would like it
to Could you just walk through each of
these and add the basic labels to them?
Just doing initial triage for me so that
I don't need to make that many
decisions. One thing you're probably
thinking is how does the agent know what
can be actioned and what's even like a
good candidate to be actioned? Well,
inside the repo I have a dot out of
scope directory right at the top here,
which is a few things that I've already
triaged with the skill that marks it.
Basically, anything that I say, "Okay,
we're not going to do this." It
basically says, "Okay, you're going to
mark this feature as out of scope for
the future." So, for instance,
Sandcastle does not provide an
abstraction layer for composing
Dockerfiles or managing base images
programmatically. This is essentially
like an architectural decision record,
but specifically for features that we're
not going to implement. So, this means
that the agent, when it's looking at
issues, especially enhancement issues,
is essentially looking at the ADRs that
I've created at these out of scope
references and going, "Okay, I can just
close this straight away because this is
an enhancement that we're not going to
commit to." Okay, it's gone ahead now
and it's labeled a bunch of these. So,
it's labeled all of these as bugs and
all of these as enhancement and mark
them all as needs triage. Let's just
work down from the bugs first since
those are going to be, I think, a little
easier to grok.
Could you start with 477 for me? Let's
fire this off and see what happens. All
right, so it's come back with saying,
"Okay, a recommendation, it is a bug."
And it's recommending that I move it to
ready for agent. It's already had
substantial triage notes pinpointing the
exact root cause, reproduced with a
stack trace, etc., etc. However, I think
I want it to actually reproduce it
itself. It's being a little bit too
credulous about the
you know, about the stuff that it's
received from the person who's tried
this. So, I would like it to use another
skill of mine to say, "Diagnose this
yourself." going to make it walk through
essentially
reproducing the bug and trying to fix
the bug. So, we're actually going to do
this from within this same session. Now,
of course, whenever I'm doing anything,
anything with the LLM, I'm thinking
about my context usage, which is in the
bottom left here. I've sort of have a
budget of 100K for this session. We're
at 46.5K, that seems fine to me. We've
certainly got enough context to diagnose
this and fix this. I I a feeling this
error is just a small error, so that's
what's at the back of my mind all the
time. What's nice about the triage too
is that, you know, we've already marked
everything as it needs to, essentially,
so it's already labeled correctly. In a
future triage session, I would just go
back to the issues and I would just say,
"Okay, let's do this issue now." It's
funny how much of AI and how much of
managing AFK agents is essentially queue
management. This is what we're doing
here. We're just sort of pruning a queue
and acting as a translation layer
between the humans creating these
tickets and the AI that's going to
implement them. The way that my plan
prompt works for Sandcastle, which is my
AFK agent kind of software factory
thing, is it looks for the label ready
for agent and it only touches ones that
have been explicitly marked ready for
agent. Okay, it looks like it has found
the issue, so diagnosis confirmed. So,
the issue is is that a couple of
variables contain a literal task ID and
this particular syntax here, if it's not
passed in by the user, actually results
in an error. So, what it's saying is we
need to replace these task IDs with an
ID, so this kind of pattern here, and
that non kind of double curly brace
placeholder will actually not cause an
error, so that'll be fine. We can see
it's also added an idea of a feedback
loop here. So, a unit test scaffolding
simple loop and asserting that the
resulting prompt dot md
contains no unresolved task ID. That
looks great and it seems to be just
busting on with it without asking, which
is is fine in this case. We can see that
the diagnose skill actually uses a
similar setup to my TDD skill, where it
gets it to create the regression test
first, create the feedback loop first,
and then fix it within that feedback
loop. So, it's looking good. It's
created the full suite and the type
check and it looks like it's just ready
to go. So, this is another nice feature
of triage, which is once you've pulled
in the issue and understand it and
diagnosed it, you can just fix it there
and then if you want to. One thing I
often like to do is when I'm doing these
is actually have a two sessions running
at once. Is have one session over here
where I'm fixing a or triaging one issue
and then one session over on the left
here where I might actually be using
main to fix the issue. Okay, it's giving
me some kind of command request here.
I'm just going to say yes and then I'm
going to bump it into auto mode. All
right, so looking pretty good. It's
added a change set. It's added a fix
here. I'm going to get it to push this
to main and close the original issue.
One thing I could do is I could get it
to create a PR and then the PR would
reference the issue originally so that
when I closed or
when I merge the PR it would close the
issue. That's how I usually like to
work. But let's just push this to main.
I actually kind of did a bit of vetting
on this beforehand. I actually know what
the fix is and this is the fix. So a bit
of movie magic for you. So that is the
triage skill. It's essentially a way of
you and the AI working together to turn
messy human ideas into actual real tasks
that the agent can pick up and work on.
And this is specifically designed for
AFK agents. So you, in order to get your
agent working properly, you need a
backlog of tasks that it can pick up
over time. And having specific labels
for each of those means that the agent
is not going to stumble around on crap
tasks that aren't ready for it yet. And
the ready for agent kind of signal is a
really cool one because you just get to
see your backlog fill up with these
little marks that you know will be
implemented. Very cool. This also
matches well with my existing skills.
For instance, we can create PRDs here.
For instance, this is one about work
tree locking to prevent concurrent agent
access. This is a PRD and I've marked it
as ready for agent. So the agent will
see this, will pick it up. You can also
do this for tickets as well. So tickets
based on PRDs. This has the parent of
the PRD that we just saw and it's also
ready for agent. So that's going to be
seen by the AI picking this up. If you
dig this then you should check out the
skills page on AI Hero below here. I'm
adding all of the change logs onto this
page which are video change logs and
article change logs, so you can keep up
to date with what's happening. And you
can sign up to this newsletter, so you
get all my latest and greatest skill
updates, as well as tips on getting the
most out of agents. You may have also
noticed that this video is in a slightly
different style from my usual videos.
It's a little less cutty. I'm
experimenting with like a different
silence detection algorithm, and I'm
interested to know what you think. I
hope these sort of slightly longer takes
have a slightly more relaxed feel, a
little bit less relentless, and you get
a sense for my kind of natural speaking
cadence, sort of separate from YouTube.
So, if you dig this, let me know.
Anyway, thanks for watching, and I'll
see you very soon.